Jeff Lukas

DESIGNER

Highly creative and multi-talented Brand Strategist and Designer with experience in digital, marketing, and print design. Adept at visual strategy, layout development, and electronic production for digital media. Excel in cross-collaboration with team environments calling for creative brainstorming to bring ideas from concepts to execution.

COMPETENCIES:

Concept Development
Color Theory
Visual Ideation
Storytelling
Layout
Digital & Print Design
Production Design
Creativity
Branding
Image Optimization
Complex Problem Solving

TECHNICAL SKILLS:

HTML5 CSS3 Bootstrap JavaScript Adobe Illustrator Adobe Photoshop Adobe InDesign Adobe After Effects Adobe Acrobat Sublime Notepad ++ GitHub Wireframes CC Atom.io

Google Ad Manager

Microsoft Office

EDUCATION:

Hubspot

BFA IN GRAPHIC DESIGN & WEB DESIGN

Project Management Software

Art Institute of Washington 2015

AA IN LIBERAL ARTS

Northern VA Community College 2007

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE:

TCG: The Creative Group (Robert Half) - Washington, DC GRAPHIC/DIGITAL DESIGNER • 01/2019 - PRESENT

Filled a variety of roles including, but not limited to, digital designer, graphic designer and presentation designer. Project highlights:

- Designed web banners and advertisement for web and mobile displays
- Developed social media graphics and event advertisements.
- Collaborated with copy editors and writers to develop various marketing collateral.
- Edited photos for collateral and designed graphic mockups for new office.
- Developed infographics for print and web usage to make complex information easier to read and more appealing.

DIGITAL DESIGNER • 06/2019 - 09/2019

Worked with the Design and Production teams at Society of Human Resource Management (SHRM) to develop and produce marketing collateral (flyers, promotional materials, and digital graphics).

- Produced new design items while retouching images for print and website usage.
- Created infographics and marketing collateral for company's presentations, magazine publications, and external usage.

Northern Virginia Magazine, Chantilly, VA

GRAPHIC DESIGNER • 01/2023 - 05/2024

Worked with the Art Director to produce the Monthly Magazine.

- Managed and directed photographers to capture compelling feature/sub-feature art/image for the publication.
- Worked with the writing team to provide art direction for the monthly cover.
- In charge of design process and advertising for external clients.
- Executed dynamic layouts for the monthly features, sub-features, client profiles and external clients advertisements.
- Provided graphics for website/social media usage, event displays, and general branding.
- Designed the new 2024 "Faces of NoVA" section of the magazine, to be used annually.

Thurgood Marshall College Fund - Washington, DC

GRAPHIC DESIGNER • 05/2015 - 08/2018

Designed advertisements and collateral for publication in print/digital media. Partnered with internal and external clients to design and develop collateral for events and campaigns.

- Ensured deadlines were adhered to from initial creative brief and concept execution to print deadlines and uploading web content.
- Designed and established the organization's internal/external brand guidelines.
- Managed print scheduling, vendors, and deadlines for all projects, events and collateral.
- Worked with marketing team to implement consistent branding across all platforms.

Ikon Realty, Springfield, VA

GRAPHIC DESIGNER • 2011 - 2018

Collaborated with head broker to create and produce employment, agent and property advertisements.

- Designed flyers and advertisements for agents and their properties.
- Photographed and edited agent photos for stationary.